Scientists Collection 1563-1973 Mss.509.L56
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1563-1973; 5.0 lin. feet 10 upright boxes, 8 oversize folders.
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1858 Nov. 6; Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873
  - Letter to Lambden, W., 1858 Nov. 16; Wagner, William
  - Letter to Henslow, J. S. (John Stevens), 1796-1861, 1858 Nov. 17; Lankester, E. Ray, Sir, (Edwin Ray), 1847-1929
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1859 Feb. 10; Cox, William Sands, 1802-1875
  - Letter to Bates, Henry, 1859 May 30; Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892
  - Autograph, 1859 Jun. 8; Loomis, Elias
  - Letter to Bond, Richard, 1859 Jul. 25; Peters, Christian Heinrich Friedrich, 1813-1890
  - Letter to Child, David Lee, 1794-1874, 1859 Sep. 20; Wilder, Burt Green, 1841-1925
  - Letter to Gray, Mrs., 1859 Dec. 3; Cayley, Arthur, 1821-1895
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1859 Dec. 21; Phillips, John, 1800-1874
  - Letter to Riise, Albert Heinrich, 1810-1882, 1860 Jan. 28; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    1965-1356c.ms
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1860 Jan. 31; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1860 Feb. 1; Murray, John, 1808-1892
    1975-1459ms
  - Letter to Riise, Albert Heinrich, 1810-1882, 1860 Mar. 29; Lyman, Theodore, 1833-1897
  - Letter to Coggswell, Dr., 1860 May 9; E. Walkers Sons
  - Letter to Riise, Albert Heinrich, 1810-1882, 1860 May 17; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    1965-1346b.ms
  - Letter to Stevens, Isaac Ingalls, 1860 Jun. 11; Suckley, George
  - Letter to Hayes, Isaac, 1860 Jun. 28; Beaumont, Victor
    Letter and brochure "Metallic Thermometers and Barometers" manufactured by Beaumont. Refers to two thermometers supplied to Hayes.
  - Note, 1860 Aug. 19; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Strachey, Edward, 1860 Aug. 24; Babington, Churchill
  - Letter to Suckley, George, 1860 Aug. 31; Cassin, John, 1813-1869
  - Letter to Suckley, George, 1860 Sep. 15; Cooper, James Graham, 1830-1902
  - Letter to "Gent.", 1860 Sep. 22; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1860 Oct. 2; Mathieu, L.
  - Letter to Humphry, George Murray, 1860 Nov. 11; Hyrtl, Joseph, 1811-1894
    1967-1220ms
  - Letter to Suckley, George, 1860 Nov. 17; Putnam, F. W., (Frederic Ward), 1839-1915
  - Letter to Mackenlyn, Miss, 1860 Nov. 22; Fairbairn, William, Sir, 1789-1874
  - Note, 1861 Jan. 5; Babbage, Charles, 1791-1871
  - Letter to Layard, Edgar Leopold, 1824-1900, 1861 Mar. 18; Günther, A.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1861 Apr. 11; Stokes, G. G.
  - Letter to Gilchrist, Alexander, 1861 Apr. 15; Woolner, Thomas
  - Letter to Riise, Albert Heinrich, 1810-1882, 1861 May 30; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
  - Letter to Sir, 1861 Jun. 7; Elliotson, John, 1791-1868
  - Letter to Suckley, George, 1861 Jun. 22; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to Way, Albert, 1805-1874, 1861 Jun. 26; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Letter to Wood, Horatio C., 1861 Jul. 10; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
  - Letter to Carpenter, William, 1797-1874, 1861 Jul. 15; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Riise, Albert Heinrich, 1810-1882, 1862 Jan. 6; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
  - Letter to Marriner, Goodwin, 1862 Jan. 18; Jenner, William, Sir, 1815-1898
  - Letter to Hays, Isaac, 1862 Jan. 27; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    1962-750ms
  - Letter to United States. Army. Medical Examining Board, 1862 Feb. 13; Carson, Joseph, 1808-1876
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1862 Feb. 24; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1862 Feb. 26; Faye, H. (Hervé), 1814-1902
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Apr. 3; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1862 Apr. 10; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1862 Apr. 26; Cope, E. D., (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Unlocated May 2011. Possibly misidentified Riise letter of the same date.
  - Letter to Riise, A[lbert] H[einrich], 1862 Apr. 26; Cope, E. D., (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    1965 2170ms
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Apr. 27; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 May 10; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Dockray, Benjamin, 1862 May 28; Wood, J. G. (John George), 1827-1889
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 May 30; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Jun. 5; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1862 Jun. 6; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Jun. 6; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Jun. 6; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Jun. 17; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Rugg, M. M., 1862 Jul. 10; Bedford, Gunning S.
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Jul. 23; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Jul. 29; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Jul. 29; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Sep. 4; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Oct. 27; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1862 Oct. 30; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1862 Nov. 1; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Browne, G. Mansfield, 1862 Nov. 14; Wallach, G. A.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1862 Nov. 20; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
  - Obituary & portrait, 1862; Brodie, Benjamin, Sir, 1783-1862
  - Layout for spine title of his edition of Buffon's correspondence, 1862; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Carson, Joseph, 1808-1876, 1863 Jan. 16; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1863 Jan. 19; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1863 Apr. 15; Murray, John, 1808-1892
    Originally dated 1862; amended. After publication and reviews of Bates' Naturalist on the River Amazon (1863), see 1892 ed.
  - Letter to Fairholt, Frederick William, 1814-1866, 1863 Jun. 4; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Letter to Way, Albert, 1805-1874, 1863 Sep. 19; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1863 Sep. 24; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Riise, Albert Heinrich, 1810-1882, 1863 Oct. 27; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to Gray, Mrs., 1863 Dec. 16; Greville, Robert Kaye, 1794-1866
  - AMs, Concerning fields of science, 1863 Dec. 19; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    1963-2110ms
  - Letter to Gray, Mrs., 1863 Dec. 21; Greville, Robert Kaye, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Gould, Augustus A. (Augustus Addison), 1805-1866, 1864 Jan. 23; Tryon, George Washington, 1838-1888
  - Letter to Brigham, William J., 1864 Feb. 15; Wyman, Jeffries, 1814-1874
  - Letter to Edward, 1864 May 19; Silliman, Benjamin, Jr., 1816-1885
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1864 May 29; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1864 Jun. 2; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Letter to Bogue, A., 1864 Jul. 21; Newman, Edward
  - Letter to Smithsonian Institution, 1864 Sep.; Faraday, Michael, 1791-1867
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1864 Nov. 3; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
  - Letter to Gray, Mrs., 1864 Dec. 21; Cayley, Arthur, 1821-1895
  - Letter to Gray, Joseph Alexander, 1884-1966, 1864 Dec. 30; Greville, Robert Kaye, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Simmons, Mr., 1865 Jan. 27; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1865 Jan. 31; Carpenter, Philip Pearsall, 1819-1877
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1865 Feb. 1; Jenner, William, Sir, 1815-1898
  - Letter to Rothrock, Joseph Trimble, 1839-1922, 1865 Mar. 2; Leidy, Joseph, 1823-1891
  - Letter to Rowland, Sir, 1865 May 29; Armstrong, W. J.
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1865 May 29; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Vesseloffsky, M. G., 1865 Jul. 2; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
  - Letter to William, 1865 Jul. 7; Gosse, Philip Henry, 1810-1888
  - Letter to Milne-Edwards, Alphonse, 1835-1900, 1865 Jul. 27; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
  - Letter to Whitney, J. D. (Josiah Dwight), 1819-1895, 1865 Aug. 17; Lesquereux, Leo, 1806-1889
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1865 Sep. 11; Carpenter, Philip Pearsall, 1819-1877
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1865 Sep. 11; Wright, Edward Perceval, 1834-1910
  - Letter to Roberts, E. H., 1865 Sep. 20; Peters, Christian Heinrich Friedrich, 1813-1890
    1967-703ms
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1865 Oct. 8; Carpenter, Philip Pearsall, 1819-1877
  - Letter to Manby, Charles, 1865 Nov. 7; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871
  - Letter to Hays, Isaac Israel, 1865 Nov. 13; Smithsonian Institution.
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1865 Dec. 20; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1866 Feb. 15; Whewell, William, 1794-1866
  - Letter to Wyan, G. W., 1866 Mar. 11; Fairbairn, William, Sir, 1789-1874
  - Note on Prof. Sabiene, 1866 May 11; Poggendorff, J. C., (Johann Christian), 1796-1877
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1866 May 29; Geikie, Archibald, Sir, 1835-1924
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1866 Jul. 31; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1866 Aug. 11; Hugo, Joseph Léopold Sigisbert, comte, 1773-1828
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1866 Oct. 2; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
  - Letter to Wood, Horatio C., 1866 Oct. 21; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
  - Note on Philip Mason, 1866 Oct. 26; Buchanan, George, 1831-1895
  - Letter to Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878, 1866 Dec. 4; Faraday, Sarah
  - Letter to Stevenson, Henry, 1867 Jan. 20; Seebohm, Henry, 1832-1895
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1867 Jan. 31; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1867 Feb. 2; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1867 Feb. 7; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1867 Feb. 7; Robson, W.
  - Letter to Wallace, Alfred Russel, 1823-1913, 1867 Feb. 9; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
    1977-1442ms
  - Letter to Bennett, W. C., 1867 Feb. 11; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
    1968-799ms
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1867 Feb. 18; Robson, W.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1867 Apr. 8; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Riise, Albert Heinrich, 1810-1882, 1867 Apr. 22; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1867 May 3; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
  - Letter to Wilson, Joseph, 1867 Jun. 20; Cassin, John, 1813-1869
  - Letter to Roberts, E. H., 1867 Jul. 9; Peters, Christian Heinrich Friedrich, 1813-1890
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1867 Jul. 12; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1867 Sep. 20; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1867 Oct. 11; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Mitchell, S. Weir (Silas Weir), 1829-1914, 1867 Oct. 23; Wyman, Jeffries, 1814-1874
  - Letter to East Indian Company, 1867 Nov. 5; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
    Regarding the standardization of weights and measures in India, and Herschel's opposition to the metric system.
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1867 Dec. 3; Murray, John, 1808-1892
    Cf. other letters referring to Bates's work on the DeChailla book in 1867.
  - Letter to Noble, William, 1867 Dec. 4; Birt, William Radcliffe, 1804-1881
    1984-519ms
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1868 Feb. 2; Baude, E.
  - Letter to Noble, William, 1868 Feb. 12; Birt, William Radcliffe, 1804-1881
  - Letter to Holloway, R. H., 1868 Feb. 21; Wheatstone, Charles, Sir, 1802-1875
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1868 May 5; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1868 May 12; Nolan, Edward J.
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1868 May 29; Binney, W. G.
  - Letter to Renouard, Jules, 1868 Jun. 27; Nadault de Buffon, Henri, 1831-1890
  - Letter to Noble, William, 1868 Jul. 24; Birt, William Radcliffe, 1804-1881
  - Letter to Noble, William, 1868 Sep. 12; Birt, William Radcliffe, 1804-1881
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1868 Oct. 15; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
  - Letter to Noble, William, 1868 Oct. 28; Birt, William Radcliffe, 1804-1881
  - Letter to Noble, William, 1868 Oct. 30; Birt, William Radcliffe, 1804-1881
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1868 Oct. 31; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1868 Nov. 12; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1868 Nov. 18; Baude, E.
  - Letter to Staehli, Dr., 1868 Nov. 27; Lyman, Theodore, 1833-1897
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1868 Dec.; Seeley, Harry Govier, 1839-1909
  - Letter to United States. Senate. President, 1868; McCormick, Cyrus Hall
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1869 Feb. 5; Carpenter, Philip Pearsall, 1819-1877
  - Letter to Beadle, E. R., 1869 Mar. 14; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1869 Apr. 21; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1869 May 15; Huxley, Thomas Henry, 1825-1895
  - Letter to Flügel, Felix (?), 1869 Aug. 23; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1869 Aug. 25; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Maxwell, Theodore, 1869 Aug. 31; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
  - Letter to Twining, Alexander Catlin, 1869 Sep. 20; Peirce, Benjamin, 1809-1880
  - Letter to Brown, A. D., 1869 Sep.; Flügel, Felix, 1820-1904
  - Letter to "Mr. Wallace", 1869 Oct. 5; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
    1977 1442ms
  - Letter to Dobie, Dr., 1869 Oct. 25; Birt, William Radcliffe, 1804-1881
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1869 Nov. 25; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
    On same sheet is: Dec. 12, 1869: Vilken to Otto Mörch
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1869 Dec. 10; Stimpson, William, 1832-1872
    On same sheet is: Feb. 5, 1870. 0 lf6rch to "Otto.", 1965-2170ms
    Also includes 1870 Feb. 5, Mörch to "Otto."
  - Letter to Jeffereys, Mr., 1869 Dec. 20; Somerville, Mary, 1780-1872
  - Letter to Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892, 1870 Jan. 1; Murray, John, 1808-1892
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1870 Jan. 8; Cooke, M. C. (Mordecai Cubitt), 1825-
  - Letter to Thomson, Edward, 1870 Jan. 11; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Carpenter, Mr., 1870 Jan. 22; Waterhouse, George R.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1870 Jan. 29; Herschel, John F. W., Sir, (John Frederick William), 1792-1871
  - Letter to "Otto", 1870 Feb. 5; Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878
    Appended to 1869 Dec. 10, Stimpson to Mörch.
  - Letter to Brown, A. D., 1870 Mar. 25; Thomson, Edward
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1870 Mar. 30; Flügel, Felix, 1820-1904
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1870 May 18; Brown, A. D.
  - Letter to Chatto, A., 1870 May 31; Proctor, Richard A.
  - Letter to Bartram, Charlton, 1870 Oct. 21; Wyman, Jeffries, 1814-1874
  - Check to Prof. Louis Agassiz..., 1870 Nov. 15; Fields, Osgood & Co.
  - Letter to Hamlin, Hannibal, 1871 Feb. 24; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Scientists). Sends Smithsonian Institution Report for 1868, to Rev. Gould as requested.
  - Letter to Knowles, James, 1871 Feb. 25; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Sampson, M. B., 1871 Mar. 2; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Staehli, Dr., 1871 May 5; Lyman, Theodore, 1833-1897
  - Letter to Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887, 1871 May 11; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to Strahan & Company, 1871 May 28; Herschel, Margaret, Brodie
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1871 Sep. 15; Thomson, John H.
    With undated reply. 1965-2170ms
  - Letter to Deane, Ruthven, 1871 Oct. 10; Jones, J. Matthew
  - Letter to Saint-Martin, 1871 Oct. 14; Naquet, Alfred Joseph
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1871 Dec. 1; Nolan, Edward J.
  - Letter to Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887, 1871 Dec. 20; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1871 Dec. 24; Button, Fred L.
  - Letter to Hammich, Mr., 1872 Jan. 27; Jenner, Lady
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1872 Feb. 6; Thomson, John H.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1872 Feb. 17; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1872 Mar. 30; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1872 Apr. 16; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1872 May 9; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Williamson, 1872 May 27; Carruthers, William
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1872 Jun. 1; Morley, Henry
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1872 Jul. 26; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1872 Jul. 30; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1872 Aug. 2; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1872 Oct. 17; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1872 Dec. 26; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
  - List of stone age relics from Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-(?), 1872; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878, 1873 Jan. 7; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
    On same sheet is: Joseph Henry to Thomas Bland, Jan. 25, 1873; 1965-2170ms
    Also includes 25 Jan. 1873 Joseph Henry to Thomas Bland.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1873 Jan. 24; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s Bland, 1873 Jan. 25; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    On the same sheet as 7 Jan. 1873, Thomas Bland to Joseph Henry.
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1873 Mar. 10; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Allen, John, 1873 Mar. 25; Rutledge, George
  - Letter to H. J. Lynge & Sons, 1873 Mar. 30; Austin, C. K.
  - Letter to L'Estrange, A. G., 1873 May 17; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Christie, Mr., 1873 Jun. 6; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1873 Jun. 15; Dieulafoy, Georges, 1839-1911
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1873 Jun. 26; Oliver, Dr.
  - Letter to Hart, Ernest Abraham, 1835-1898, 1873 Jun. 29; Hayen, G.
  - Letter to British Medical Association, 1873 Jul. 1, 4; Blanche, Dr.
  - Letter to Hart, Ernest Abraham, 1835-1898, 1873 Jul. 4; Brücke, Ernst W. von
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1873 Jul. 15; Spiegelberg, Otto
  - Letter to British Medical Association. President, 1873 Jul. 16; Lailler, C.
  - Letter to Glück, I. R., 1873 Jul. 20; Cunie, Dr.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1873 Jul. 20; Moreau, Armand
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1873 Jul. 27; Courty, A
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1873 Aug. 3; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Kent, Charles, 1873 Aug. 20; Proctor, Richard A.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1873 Sep. 18; Evans, John
  - Letter to Hart, Mr., 1873 Oct. 29; Watson, John
  - Letter to Worsaae, Jens Jakob Asmussen, 1821-1885, 1873 Nov. 3; Rau, Charles, 1826-1887
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1873 Nov. 18; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1873 Dec. 3; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Townsend, W., 1873 Dec. 20; Hayden, F. V., (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887
  - Letter to Jessopp, Dr., 1873 Dec. 24; Bates, Henry Walter, 1825-1892
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1873 Dec. 26; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Announcement of his works on geography, 1873; Guyot, A., (Arnold), 1807-1884
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1874 Jan. 24; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
  - Letter to Duckworth, Mr., 1874 Jan. 27; Jenner, William, Sir, 1815-1898
  - Letter to Townsend, W., 1874 Jan. 29; Raymond, R. W.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1874 Jan. 31; Beadle, E. R.
  - Letter to Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887, 1874 Feb. 21; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1874 Feb. 25; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1874 Mar. 28; Prime, Temple, 1832-1903
  - Autograph, 1874 Oct. 30; Helps, Arthur
    Includes autograph, letter from Arthur Ricketts, and biography of Helps.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1874 Nov. 15; Tyndall, John, 1820-1893
  - Letter to Rooper, Miss, 1874; Hutton, R.
  - Letter to Capen, Naham, 1875 Jan. 24; Cooper, Peter, 1791-1883
    Includes letter, two reproductions of the letter, printed bio of Cooper (incomplete), and handwritten bio of Cooper.
  - Letter to Frampton, Dr., 1875 Feb. 26; Jenner, William, Sir, 1815-1898
  - Letter to Kimball, Moses, 1875 Mar. 30; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1875 Jun. 16; Carpenter, Miss
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1875 Nov. 30; Dall, William H.
  - Letter to Centennial Commission, 1875 Dec. 16; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1876 Jan. 24; Runkle, J. D.
  - Letter to Hayes, Isaac Israel, 1876 Jan. 25; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1876 Feb. 6; Burrows, George, 1801-1887
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1876 Feb. 26; Morley, John
  - Letter to Stanley, Mrs., 1876 Mar. 16; Tennant, James, 1808-1881
  - Letter to Horsford, Eben Norton, 1876 May 18; Fish, Hamilton
  - Letter to Fish, Hamilton, 1876 May 25; Horsford, Eben Norton, 1818-1893
  - Letter to Mörch, Otto Andreas Lowson, 1828-1878, 1876 Jun. 22; Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885
  - Letter to Charters, Mr., 1876 Aug. 23; Jenner, William, Sir, 1815-1898
  - Letter to Jergesen, Alf, 1876 Aug. 28; Peck, George W.
  - Letter to Jergesen, Alf, 1876 Aug. 29; Peck, George W.
  - Letter to Button, Fred L., 1876 Sep. 19; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1876 Oct. 19; Button, Fred L.
  - Letter to Button, Fred L., 1876 Nov. 22; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
  - Letter to Pontippidan, H., 1876 Nov. 24; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
  - Letter to Pontippidan, H., 1876 Dec. 1; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1877 Jan. 16; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1877 Feb. 14; Button, Fred L.
  - Letter to Shipping receipt to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1877 Feb. 27; Button, Fred L.
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1877 Mar. 4; Button, Fred L.
  - Letter to Swayne, S. H., 1877 Mar. 6; Carpenter, William B.
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1877 Mar. 27; Blunt, George W.
  - Letter to Hayes, Isaac, 1877 Apr. 7; Beach, A. E.
  - Letter to Hooker, [Joseph Dalton?], 1877 Apr. 13; Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
  - Letter to Button, Fred L., 1877 Apr. 17; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
  - Letter to White, Charles, 1877 Apr. 30; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Waterman, W. F., 1877 May 3; Lubbock, John, Sir, 1834-1913
  - Letter to Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-, 1877 May 14; Button, Fred L.
  - Recommendation for P.C.Weedman, 1877 May 23; Andrew, J.
  - Note on P. A. Steedman, 1877 May 24; Southey, Henry Herbert, 1783-1865
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1877 Jun. 7; Bourneville, Dr.
  - Letter to Button, Fred L., 1877 Jun. 7; Poulsen, Christian Marinus, 1818-
  - Letter to Unidentified recipient, 1877 Jun. 9; Berkeley, M. J., (Miles Joseph), 1803-1889
  - Letter to Hart, 1877 Jul. 11; Quain, Richard, 1816-1898